James A. Pike Papers
James A. Pike Papers
- Writings
  - Books
    - Teen-agers and Sex, research material, drafts, etc; no material relating to chapter V or IX
      - Foreword, 1965; typescript copy revised (Box 94)
      - Chapter I, 1965; typescript copy (Box 94)
      - Chapter II, 1965; draft A, typescript reproduction annotated; draft B, typescript revised; 2 folders (Box 94)
      - Chapter III, 1965; typescript reproduction annotated (Box 94)
      - Chapter IV, 1965; typescript copy annotated (Box 94)
      - Chapter VI, 1965; typescript copy annotated (Box 94)
      - Chapter VII, 1965; draft A, typescript copy annotated; draft B, typescript revised; 2 folders (Box 94)
      - Chapter VIII, 1965; typescript copy annotated (Box 94)
      - Chapter X, 1965; typescript reproduction annotated, typescript copy annotated (Box 94)
      - Chapter XI (not part of final draft), 1965; typescript revised (Box 94)
      - Final draft, printer's copy, 1965 (Box 95)
      - Book reviews, 1965; published material (Box 95)
    - A Time For Christian Candor (Chapter VIII), 1964
      - Galley fragment (Box 95)
      - Galley page proofs, 1964 (Box 95)
      - Book reviews, 1966; published material (Box 95)
    - What Is This Treasure, 1966
      - Introduction, holograph (Box 95)
      - Book reviews, published material (Box 95)
    - You and the New Morality, 1967
      - Chapters I-XV, printer's copy, typescript; 2 folders (Box 95)
      - Book reviews, printed material (Box 95)
    - Miscellaneous
      - Comments on Pike's books, 1958; typescript copy (Box 95)
      - Corrections of footnotes for unknown book, typescript annotated (Box 95)
      - Fragment on theological language, typescript copy revised (Box 95)
      - Prospectus for series of books on Christian doctrine, holograph (Box 95)
      - Reviews of books to which Pike contributed, published material (Box 95)
      - Unidentified chapters dealing with the legal profession, typescript revised (Box 95)
  - Columns
    - ["Bishop Pike Answers..."(?)], Hall Syndicate, 1958; draft A, holograph; draft B, typescript; draft C, typescript revised; draft D, typescript copy; 4 folders (Box 95)
    - "The Dean's Column," Bulletin of the Diocese of N.Y., Miscellaneous columns; holograph, typescript, typescript revised, typescript copy, typescript copy revised; published material (Box 95)
  - Forewords
    - Ferris, [Theodore Parker(?)], 1963; typescript copy (Box 95)
    - [Introduction to the Protestant Lenten Reading List], 1957; typescript copy (Box 95)
    - Davis, Jerome, Adventure for Peace, Jun 1967[?]; typescript revised (Box 95)
    - Gilbert, Arthur (co-author), Your Neighbor Celebrates, Apr 1957; typescript copy revised (Box 95)
    - Loomis, W. Farnsworth, The God Within, galley rev. (Box 96)
    - Spraggett, Allen, The Unexplained, Apr 1967; typescript revised reproduction (Box 96)
    - Yeh, Theodore T.Y., typescript copy, few items of correspondence (Box 96)
  - Interviews
    - "An Interview with Bishop Pike" Information Service, Dec 3 1966; published material (Box 96)
    - "Bishop Pike Says..." by Tim Weeks, Phoenix Gazette, Feb 3 1967; published material (Box 96)
    - "Bishop Pike's Strange Seances" by Jess Stearn, This Week, 1968(?); typescript copy revised; printed material; 2 folders (Box 96)
    - "Fewer Beliefs, More Belief" Center Diary: 14, Sep-Oct 1966; typescript repro, published material; 2 folders (Box 96)
    - "Haereticus", Oct 20 1966; typescript revised (Box 96)
    - "The Impact of the Space Age on Religion" by Linda Folkard-Stengel, 1969; typescript copy revised (Box 96)
    - "My Husband Has Lost His Religion" Cosmopolitan, Sep 1956; published material (Box 96)
    - "The Outspoken Dean" by Ann Elizabeth Price, This Week, Oct 18 1953; draft, typescript copy revised, and holograph; published material; 2 folders (Box 96)
    - "Peek at Pike" by Lawrence MacDonald, Pacifican, Dec 8, 14, 1967; published material (Box 96)
    - "Should Our Churches Unite?" by Ed Keister, Parade, Dec 31, 1961; galley rev.; published material (Box 96)
    - "Survival and Growth of Personality" by Linda Folkard-Stengel, 1969; typescript copy revised (Box 96)
    - "A Visit with Dean Pike" by Leonard Gross, Think, 1958; galley rev. (Box 96)
    - "W-5" with Allen Spragget and Arthur Ford, CTV, Toronto, Canada, Sep 3 1967; typescript reproduction (Box 96)
    - "What About San Francisco 'Sin'?" by Mary Frazer, San Francisco News, Jul 1 1958; published material (Box 96)
    - "What Bishop Pike Believes" by Ken Gaydos, Christianity Today, Nov 25 1966; published material (Box 96)
    - "Why I Am Not A Unitarian-Universalist" by William Wingfield, The Register-Leader, Nov 1965; published material (Box 96)
    - "Why I Was Expelled From Rhodesia" by Raphael Bashan, Ma'ariv, Jan 7 1966; typescript copy (Box 96)
    - Untitled
      - [Arizona Interview], by Tim Weeks, Feb 3 1967; typescript copy (Box 96)
      - [Methodist youth interview], by Hal Conklin and Scott Kennedy, Clatter, Dec 1967; published material (Box 96)
      - [On Psychic Phenomena], Cosmos, Jan and Feb 1969; published material (Box 96)
      - [Radio Interview for Episcopal Church], by Dana F. Kennedy, "Viewpoint", Apr 28 1964; printed material (Box 96)
  - Memoranda
    - "Amendment to Rules of Practice to Require Adequate Briefing of Exceptions Relied Upon in Hearing before Commission", Jan 25 1938; typescript copy (Box 96)
    - "Comment on Report of Committee on Administrative Practice of the D.C. Bar Association", typescript copy (Box 96)
    - "The Conflict of Archaism and Idealism in Institutions", typescript reproduction (Box 96)
    - "Model Complaint Annotated", typescript reproduction (Box 96)
    - "Necessity for Notice, Hearing, and Findings in the Adoption of Rules and Regulations by the Commission", Jan 31 1939; typescript (Box 96)
    - "Pointers Toward a Center Project in the Area of Religion", Feb 28 1968; typescript reproduction (Box 96)
    - "Prolegomena to the Study of the Apparent Discorrelation Between Church Involvement and Socio-Ethical Attitudes", Aug 4, 1966; typescript repro (Box 96)
  - Pamphlets
    - The Art of Living. NBC, 1966 (Box 96)
    - The Difference of Woman, and the Difference It Makes, Encyclopedia Britannica, 1966; part of "Great Ideas" series (Box 96)
  - Radio/television
    See also Recordings.
    - "America Speaks" Pike vs. Bundy on Communism in Churches, Jul 18 1953; printed material (Box 96)
    - "Bishop Pike Show", Oct 1958; publicity, printed material (Box 96)
    - "Christmas Eve Service at St. John the Divine", Dec 24 1954 (Box 96)
    - "The Crises of Modern Man" with Frederic Mayer, Los Angeles, California, 1967 (Box 96)
    - "Dean Pike Show"
      - Publicity, 1956-1957 (Box 96)
      - Freedom of religion and church-state relations under the First Amendment, 8 Oct 1955 (Box 96)
      - Problems of the people of Asia in the light of world peace, 23 Oct 1955 (Box 97)
      - Revival of religion (hosted by Cathy Pike), 30 Oct 1955 (Box 97)
      - Relationship between religion, psychiatry and psychoanalysis in the healing of men, 6 Nov 1955 (Box 97)
      - Dead Sea Scrolls, 13 Nov 1955 (Box 97)
      - What is America's responsibility for freedom in the rest of the world?, 20 Nov 1955 (Box 97)
      - Proper care of our juvenile delinquents, part 1, 27 Nov 1955 (Box 97)
      - Proper care of our juvenile delinquents, part 2, 4 Dec 1955 (Box 97)
      - Origin and development of the cross as symbol in the Christian tradition, 11 Dec 1955 (Box 97)
      - Religion and the public schools, 18 Dec 1955 (Box 97)
      - Meaning of Christmas, 25 Dec 1955 (Box 97)
      - Prospects ahead for church unity and cooperation, 1 Jan 1956 (Box 97)
      - Religion in Russia today, 8 Jan 1956 (Box 97)
      - Religion, criminal law and sex, 15 Jan 1956 (Box 97)
      - Marriage, 22 Jan 1956 (Box 97)
      - Religion and sports, 29 Jan 1956 (Box 97)
      - Divorce, 5 Feb 1956 (Box 97)
      - Relationship of Judaism and Christianity, 12 Feb 1956 (Box 97)
      - Religion and education in Israel today, 19 Feb 1956; 2 folders (Box 97)
      - Questions young boys ask about religion, 26 Feb 1956 (Box 97)
      - Ethics and politics, 4 Mar 1956 (Box 97)
      - Questions children ask about the life to come, 11 Mar 1956 (Box 97)
      - Race problem in South Africa today, 18 Mar 1956 (Box 97)
      - Freedom to read, 25 Mar 1956 (Box 97)
      - Relation of Islam and Christianity, 8 Apr 1956 (Box 97)
      - Prayer, 15 Apr 1956 (Box 97)
      - Problems of the aged, 22 Apr 1956 (Box 97)
      - Ethical responsibility of the lawyer, 29 Apr 1956 (Box 97)
      - Religious vocation of the layman, 6 May 1956 (Box 97)
      - What's happening in the country now, 13 May 1956 (Box 97)
      - Why go to church, 20 May 1956 (Box 97)
      - Religion, ethics and psychiatry, 27 May 1956 (Box 97)
      - Ferment in Africa, 18 Nov 1956 (Box 98)
      - Refugee problems, 25 Nov 1956; 2 folders (Box 98)
      - Hanukkah, 2 Dec 1956 (Box 98)
      - Religious revivals: meanings and distortions, 16 Dec 1956 (Box 98)
      - The place of women in the church's work, 30 Dec 1956 (Box 98)
      - Teenage tensions, 13 Jan 1957 (Box 98)
      - Marriage, 29 Oct 1957 (Box 98)
      - Criminals (guest Douglas C. Rigg, warden, Minnesota State Prison), 19 Nov 1957 (Box 98)
      - Religious and ethical questions of young people, 26 Nov 1957 (Box 98)
      - Traffic accidents, crime, 4 Dec 1957 (Box 98)
      - Hanukkah, 19 Dec 1957 (Box 98)
      - Advertising (guest Vance Packard, The Hidden Persuaders), 29 Dec 1957 (Box 98)
      - Art in the Christian tradition, 7 Jan 1958 (Box 98)
      - Gangs, 14 Jan 1958 (Box 98)
      - Christianity and capitalism, 21 Jan 1958 (Box 98)
      - American eating habits / family dinner, 11 Feb 1958 (Box 98)
      - Japan, 23 Feb 1958 (Box 98)
      - The single woman, 3 Mar 1958 (Box 98)
      - Latin America current events, 11 Mar 1958 (Box 98)
      - South Africa, 16 Mar 1958 (Box 98)
      - Problem of refugees, 23 Mar 1958 (Box 98)
      - Easter, 27 May 1958; 2 folders (Box 98)
      - Israel's 10th anniversary, 29 May 1958 (Box 98)
    - "Frontiers of Faith." "Christ the Hope of the World", Jun 6 1954 (Box 98)
    - "How To Handle Your Troubles", prospectus, typescript (Box 98)
    - "Jinx Falkenburg Show" with Mrs. Pike, Jan 10 1955; Mrs. Pike questions Spanish Ambassador to U.S. (Box 98)
    - "Our Protestant Heritage" with Mrs. Pike, Nov 24 1957; typescript copy revised (Box 98)
    - "Proper Care of our Juvenile Delinquents", Dec 3 1955; reviews of programs by Floris Cante (Box 98)
    - "Spotlight New York" with Dr. Kenneth R. Kinney, Jul 16 1953; discussion (Box 98)
    - "Town Meeting of the Air", 1955; 1956; includes "How Real Is Our Religious Revival?" and "Why the Excitement About Bridey Murphy?" (Box 98)
  - Sermons
    - Research material, published material, typescript, holograph (Box 98)
    - Undated and untitled, 1944-1950; holograph, typescript, typescript revised (Box 98)
    - [Teaching Mission, Christ Church, Poughkeepsie(?)], 1944(?), Mar 19-26; printed material (Box 98)
    - "God's Solution", [1945?]; typescript copy (Box 98)
    - [On John 3:16], [1945?]; typescript copy (Box 98)
    - "Man's Predicament", [1945?]; typescript revised (Box 98)
    - "There's Been So Much Talk(?)", typescript revised (Box 98)
    - "Discovery or Revelation(?), Jan [1945?]; typescript revised; typescript; 2 folders (Box 98)
    - "Examination of Conscience", Feb [1945?]; typescript revised (Box 98)
    - "In the World, But Not of It", Mar [1945?]; typescript revised (Box 98)
    - "Speak unto the children of Israel that they go forward", Apr [1945?]; drafts A and B, typescript (Box 98)
    - "Every valley shall be filled...", Jun 24 [1945?]; typescript (Box 99)
    - "Love God and Do As You Please", Jun 28 [1945?]; typescript (Box 99)
    - "From Heaven or From Men?", Jul [1945?]; typescript revised (Box 99)
    - "Be always ready to give an answer...for the hope that is in you.", Oct [1945?]; typescript revised (Box 99)
    - "Explaining the Holy Communion to Agnostics", Feb [1946?]; typescript revised (Box 99)
    - "Has Christianity Anything to Do With Economics and Politics?", Feb [1946?]; typescript (Box 99)
    - "Priesthood of all Believers", Feb [1946?]; typescript revised (Box 99)
    - "Stand fast therefore...", Feb [1946?]; typescript revised (Box 99)
    - [On types of Religion], Feb [1946?]; holograph (Box 99)
    - [On Authority], Mar [1946?]; typescript revised (Box 99)
    - "Diagnosing Your Fears", Mar [1946?]; typescript revised (Box 99)
    - "What is Truth?", Mar [1946?]; typescript revised (Box 99)
    - "Repent Ye!", Dec [1946?]; typescript revised (Box 99)
    - [On Ethics], [1947?]; typescript (Box 99)
    - "Fear not, for they that be with us are more than they that be with them.", [1947?]; typescript (Box 99)
    - "How shall I give thee up, O Ephraim?", [1947?]; typescript (Box 99)
    - [On Light in Dark World], Jan [1947?]; typescript revised (Box 99)
    - "In the year that King Uzziah died...", Mar [1947?]; typescript revised (Box 99)
    - [On God], Jun [1947?]; typescript revised (Box 99)
    - [On A "Vital Vision"], 1948(?), Apr; holograph (Box 99)
    - [On Ordination], 1949-1951; typescript revised, and published material (Box 99)
    - "The Place of Religion in a University", Oct 2, 1949; typescript copy, printed material (Box 99)
    - "The Christmas Gift", Dec 25, 1949; typescript reproduction (Box 99)
    - "Where Do We Go From Here?", Jun, 1950; published material (Box 99)
    - "In the days that were before the flood", Jun 4, 1950; printed material (Box 99)
    - "The Best Things in the Worst Times", 1951, Jun 3; printed material (Box 99)
    - "An Examination of Conscience", 1952-1958; typescript revised (Box 99)
    - "God To Men", 1952-1958; typescript revised (Box 99)
    - "Judaism and Christianity", 1952-1958; typescript (Box 99)
    - "Judgment", 1952-1958; typescript copy (Box 99)
    - "Mr. Chambers' 'Witness'", 1952-1958; typescript revised (Box 99)
    - [On Children and Violence], 1952-1958; typescript copy revised (Box 99)
    - "The Reconciliation of Self-Criticism and Self-Acceptance", 1952-1958; typescript copy (Box 99)
    - "Religion as Perspective", 1952-1958; draft A, typescript copy revised; draft B, typescript; 2 folders (Box 99)
    - [On Freedom, Religion and Education", Apr 11, 1952; draft A, typescript; draft B, typescript copy; 2 folders (Box 99)
    - "The Educators' Current Assault on Democracy in the Name of Democracy", Apr 20, 1952; draft A, typescript copy revised; draft B, typescript copy; 2 folders (Box 99)
    - [Cornell Baccalaureate Service], Jun 8, 1952; typescript revised (Box 99)
    - "What Think Ye of Christ?", Oct 12, 1952; typescript copy (Box 99)
    - "Election Day and All Saint's Day", Nov 2, 1952; typescript copy (Box 99)
    - "The Christian Citizen", Nov 16, 1952; typescript copy (Box 99)
    - "The Life Everlasting", Dec 1952; typescript copies, some with revisions; 5 folders (Box 99)
      Part I, Death; Part II, On Sainthood; Part III, Hell; Part IV, Heaven; Part V, On Eternity
    - [On Scripture], Dec 7, 1952; printed material (Box 99)
    - [On the Seminary as the Church], 1953; typescript copy (Box 99)
    - [On Planned Parenthood, the Health and Welfare Council, and the Roman Catholic Church]', Jan 25, 1953; draft A, printed material; draft B, printed material; 2 folders (Box 99)
    - [On Cooperation Between Community Groups], Feb 15, 1953; printed material (Box 99)
    - "Jesus' Temptation in the Wilderness", Feb 22, 1953; typescript copy (Box 99)
    - [On the Passion of Christ], Mar 29, 1953; draft A (with corrections), printed material; draft B, printed material; 2 folders (Box 99)
    - [On the Resurrection], Apr 12, 1953; printed material (Box 99)
    - [On God's Relationship to Man], Apr 19, 1953; printed material (Box 99)
    - "The Christian's Dual Citizenship", Apr 26, 1953; printed material (Box 99)
    - "The Meaning of the Trinity", May 3, 1953; incomplete; printed material (Box 99)
    - "The War in Heaven Today" Advance, May 4, 1953; Jun 1958; typescript copy revised; published material; 2 folders (Box 99)
    - "Does Prayer Change Things", May 10, 1953; printed material (Box 99)
    - "Christ's Reign and Social Action", May 17, 1953; typescript copy (Box 99)
    - [On Charges of Communism in Churches], Jul 5, 1953; printed material (Box 99)
    - "If This Be Treason..." Churchman, Jul 5, 1953; published material (Box 99)
    - "Fear", Jul 5, 1953; draft A, typescript and printed material; draft B, printed material; 2 folders (Box 99)
    - "Frustration", Jul 19, 1953; typescript (Box 99)
    - "Inhibition", Jul 26, 1953; typescript and printed material (Box 99)
    - [On Reformation], preached at Briggs Stadium, Detroit, Michigan, Oct 25, 1953; draft A, typescript copy revised; draft B, printed material; 2 folders (Box 99)
    - [On Reformation], preached in Buffalo, New York, Nov 1, 1953; typescript copy revised, typescript revised (Box 99)
    - [On Christians' Indifference to Their Faith", Nov 8[?] 1953; printed material (Box 99)
    - "The Present Meaning of the Future Life", Nov 8, 1953; printed material (Box 99)
    - "Praying For Others", Nov 15, 1953; printed material (Box 99)
    - [On Christian Ministry], Dec 13, 1953; draft A, typescript copy; draft B, printed material; 2 folders (Box 99)
    - [On Christmas], Dec 25, 1953; printed material (Box 99)
    - [On St. John's Day], Dec 27, 1953; printed material (Box 99)
    - [On Authority and Freedom in Religion], Jan 10, 1954; typescript (Box 99)
    - [On Marriage of Cana in Galilee], Jan 24, 1954; printed material (Box 99)
    - [On Centurion at Crucifixion], Jan 31, 1954; printed material (Box 99)
    - "How To Die", Feb 14, 1954; printed material (Box 99)
    - [On Heaven and Hell], Feb 21, 1954; printed material (Box 99)
    - [On Being Co-Workers With God], Mar 7, 1954; printed material (Box 99)
    - [On McCarthyism], Mar 21, 1954; preached at Washington Cathedral, printed material; Episcopal Churchnews, Apr 18 1954, published material; 2 folders (Box 99)
    - [On Reactions to Sermon about McCarthyism], Mar 28, 1954; printed material (Box 99)
    - "Guilt" preached at Charleston, S.C., Mar 31, 1954; draft A, typescript and printed material; draft B, printed material; 2 folders (Box 99)
    - [On Atonement], Apr 4, 1954; printed material (Box 99)
    - [On God's Relationship to Man], May 2, 1954; printed material (Box 99)
    - "The Supreme Court Decision on Segregation in the Schools is a Judgement on the Church", May 23, 1954; typescript copy (Box 99)
    - [On Church Unity], Jun 6, 1954; typescript copy (Box 99)
    - "The Church in Politics" dialogue sermon with Canon John Pyle, Jul 11, 1954; printed material (Box 100)
    - [On Marriage and Religion], Jul 18, 1954; printed material (Box 100)
    - "Isn't the Church Too Slow About Taking Political Action?" dialogue sermon with Canon John Pyle, Jul 18, 1954; printed material (Box 100)
    - "Hasn't the Church Itself Been Influenced by the Communist Line?" dialogue sermon with Canon John Pyle, Jul 25, 1954; printed material (Box 100)
    - "Religion and Sleep", Sep 26, 1954; printed material (Box 100)
    - [On God's Actions Toward Human Needs], Oct 3, 1954; printed material (Box 100)
    - "The Truth About Death" Ninth Annual Episcopal Hour, Oct 24, 1954; published material (Box 100)
    - "What About Miracles?", Oct 24, 1954; typescript copy (Box 100)
    - "The Truth About Judgement" Ninth Annual Episcopal Hour, Oct 31, 1954; published material (Box 100)
    - "The Truth About Hell" Ninth Annual Episcopal Hour, Nov 7, 1954; published material (Box 100)
    - "Two Phases of Faith", Nov 7, 1954; typescript copy revised (Box 100)
    - "The Truth About Heaven" Ninth Annual Episcopal Hour, Nov 14, 1954; published material (Box 100)
    - [On the Uniqueness of Christ], Dec 25, 1954; typescript copy revised (Box 100)
    - [On St. Stephen's Day], Dec 26, 1954; draft A, typescript copy; draft B, printed material; 2 folders (Box 100)
    - [On Dangers of Religious Upsurge], preached at Congregation Rodeph Shalom, New York City, 1955; printeJan 15, d material (Box 100)
    - "Judaism and Christianity", Jan 16, 1955; draft A, typescript copy revised; draft B, printed material; 2 folders (Box 100)
    - "How To Handle A Sense of Guilt" Presbyterian Life, Mar 5, 1955; published material (Box 100)
    - "Religion and Psychiatry Today", Mar 13, 1955; printed material (Box 100)
    - "Independence of Spirit Means A Cross", The Churchman, Mar 27, 1955; May 1 1955; printed material; published material; 2 folders (Box 100)
    - "How To Suffer Without Tragedy", Apr 3, 1955; draft A, typescript copy revised draft B, typescript; 2 folders (Box 100)
    - "What Do We Know About the Life To Come?", Apr 17, 1955; printed material (Box 100)
    - "The Life Everlasting" Pulpit Digest, May, 1955; published material (Box 100)
    - "The Perils of Over-Calculativeness", May 1, 1955; draft A, typescript copy; draft B, printed material; 2 folders (Box 100)
    - "'The New Yorker' on the Dead Sea Scrolls and the Uniqueness of Christ", May 22, 1955; printed material (Box 100)
    - "How God Reveals Himself", May 29, 1955; typescript copy (Box 100)
    - "How Free Are We To Choose?", Jul 10, 1955; typescript copy revised (Box 100)
    - "The American Christian and South Africa" preached in Corlears Hook Amphitheater, New York, Jul 16, 1955; typescript copy (Box 100)
    - "Are the Rules of Ethics Permanent or Do They Change?", Jul 17, 1955; draft A, typescript revised draft B, typescript copy; 2 folders (Box 100)
    - "Ethical Influence and Religious Divisions", Nov 6, 1955; typescript copy revised (Box 100)
    - "How To Live Dangerously", 1956; incomplete; typescript copy, typescript (Box 100)
    - "Christian Faith and the Search for Bridey Murphy", Apr 22, 1956; draft A, typescript copy revised; draft B, printed material; 2 folders (Box 100)
    - On Church Unity], preached in Convention Hall, Philadelphia, Pa., May 27, [1956; printed material (Box 100)
    - [On the Inner Sources of Ethical Behavior], Jul 8, 1956; typescript copy (Box 100)
    - " Baby Doll and the Advent Message", Dec 23, 1956; first draft and final draft, typescript copies; 2 folders (Box 100)
    - "The Christmas Gift" Lay Reader's Sermon, Dec 30, 1956; printed material (Box 100)
    - "How To Meet Temptation", Mar 14, 1957; typescript copy (Box 100)
    - "Did Jesus Have To Die?", Apr 7, 1957; draft A, typescript copy revised; draft B, printed material; 2 folders (Box 100)
    - [On Legal Ethics], American Bar Association Service, Jul 14, 1957; typescript copy revised (Box 100)
    - "On Living Adventurously", Jul 21, 1957; drafts A and B, typescript copies revised; draft C, printed material; 3 folders (Box 100)
    - [On God's Incarnation], Dec 24, 1957; printed material (Box 100)
    - "On Living Adventurously" Bulletin, All Saints Church, California, 1958; published material (Box 100)
    - "What Is The Christian Faith", May 11, 1958; printed material (Box 100)
    - "How To Avoid Frustration", Jun 22, 1958; typescript revised (Box 100)
    - [On Church Unity], preached at Mancini Bowl, Modesto, California, Aug 31, 1958; typescript (Box 100)
    - "The Truth About Judgment" Pulpit Digest, 1959; Feb 1959; published material (Box 100)
    - "Will Krushchev See the Real America?", Sep 6, 1959; printed material (Box 100)
    - "The Apostles' Doctrine and Fellowship" Pacific Churchman, Nov 14, 1959; Jan 1960; published material (Box 100)
    - [On Agnosticism and Faith], preached at University of Chicago, Jan, 1960; typescript revised (Box 100)